This is the final stage, Nagai.
（佐藤(さとう)）
最終ステージだ　永井(ながい)君
（佐藤）
ハハハハ…！
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
黒い幽霊！
Black ghost!
なんで 他人を気遣えるんですか？
How is it that you're able
to worry about others?
（野村(のむら)）
逃げ… ろ
Run.
（圭）
嫌だ　あんたは助けたい
No. I want to save you.
（佐藤）
ふん！
うっ… ぐわっ…
うわあー！
（モニター音声:キャスター）
あ！　永井圭が川へ！
Nagai dove into the river!
自らも川へ飛び降りました！
He dove into the river!
（どよめき）
The river is swollen and muddied--
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
くっ…
（岸(きし)）
ふん！
Goddamn it.
（太居(ふとい)）
何ということだ…
Let's go. The sample got away.
（オグラ･イクヤ）
帰ろう　サンプルは逃げた
What's going on with Hat?
帽子の方は どうなってるんだ？
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
あ… どの監視カメラにも
見当たりません
I can't see him on any
of the surveillance cameras.
永井圭奪取が目的なら
既に立ち去ったのでは…
If getting Nagai was his goal,
then he may have already left...
（携帯の着信音）
あっ…
Mr. Tosaki.
（泉）
戸崎さん…
You remain here.
君は ここにいろ
This is Tosaki.
はい 戸崎です
I'll connect you with the Minister.
（秘書）
大臣に おつなぎします
The bosses are not happy, Tosaki.
（大臣）
社長たちが怒っているぞ 戸崎
I'm terribly sorry...
申し訳ありません
At this rate,
we may have to reconsider your position.
（大臣）
このままでは お前の担当も
考え直さなければならん
Yes, sir.
はい
Or perhaps it won't just stop at that.
（大臣）
いや それだけでは済まされんな
覚悟しておけ
Consider yourself warned.
（電話の切れる音）
（戸崎）うっ…
くっ…
やあ 待たせたね
Hey, sorry to keep you waiting.
You're late, Mr. Sato.
（田中功次(たなかこうじ)）
遅いっすよ 佐藤さん
Well, Nagai was quite interesting,
so, I played with him a bit.
（佐藤）
いやぁ 永井くんが面白い感じに
動くから遊んじゃったよ
Sometimes it helps to pretend to be angry.
怒ったふりも してみるもんだね
We've done a lot so far, but...
さて いろいろやったけど―
this is what we're really here for.
ここからが本題だよ
AJIN: DEMI-HUMAN
Do you sleep well?
深く眠れるかい？
傷は癒せたかい？
Did your wounds heal?
Just cos' they say the night is lonely
夜が寂しいからって
You don't have to force yourself
To love someone
無理して
誰かを愛さないで
They say I'm dreaming
夢を見る事だって
咽び泣く事だって
They say I'm sobbing
知りもしないまま
死んでみたって
They say I tried to die without knowing
上手に隠れたかい？
息は潜めたかい？
Did you manage to hide?
Did you hold your breath?
Just cos' they say it's tough now
You don't have to force yourself to change
今が苦しいからって
無理して自分変えないで
Even a brave savage
勇敢な蛮人だって
悩める子羊だって
Even a troubled lamb
They are just wandering through life
回り道して生きているって
目立たないように
So I don't stand out
So I can put up with it
堪えられるように
So my train of thought won't stop yet
思考回路はまだ
止めないように
今宵 RUN A WAY  RUN A WAY
Tonight run away, run a way
It's unbelievable
嘘みたいだ
誰かこの手
掴んでくれよ
Someone take my hand
The tomorrow we can't see
Doesn't have to come
見えない明日は来なくていい
今はただ 眠りたい
Now I just want to sleep
I SWEAR I'LL COVER THE WHOLE THING UP
（戸崎）
はぁっ…
（大臣）
それだけでは済まされんな
Or perhaps it won't stop at that.
覚悟しておけ
Consider yourself warned.
Screw them.
（戸崎）
ふざけるな
何のために
ここまでやって来たと思ってる
What do you think
I've come this far for...?
何のために…
For what...?
くっ… くっ…
You called for me, Minister?
（戸崎）
お呼びでしょうか 大臣
Tosaki, I've heard a lot about you.
（大臣）
戸崎君 話は聞いているよ
They say you're quite capable.
有能なんだってねぇ
Yes, well... I'm still learning.
いえ そんな… まだまだです
And that... you can be quite discreet.
そして “口が堅い”とも
You know about
the Ajin Control Commission, right?
亜人管理委員会は
君も知っているだろう？
あそこの担当に 空きが出来てね
We now have an opening there.
Tosaki...
戸崎君
Do you like money?
金は好きか？
That gun of yours... is it real...?
（戸崎）
その銃 本物なのか？
（木戸(きど)）
あ？　ああ…
Yeah. As long as you have money,
just about anything's possible.
金さえあれば
大抵のことは どうにでもなる
What does an organization
for Ajin research and control...
亜人の研究･管理が目的の組織が
どう 金とつながる？
have to do with money?
フッ… すぐに分かるさ
You'll understand shortly.
（心電計のアラーム）
あっ あぁっ…
Number 002, killed instantly.
（アナウンス）
002番 即死です
What you just witnessed is
a military weapons test.
（木戸）
今 行われているのは
軍事兵器の性能テストだ
So, then you lend out Ajins for testing?
亜人を貸し出してるってわけか…
Very good...
You're as quick as they say you are.
さすが 出世頭は察しがいいな
Yes... we have underground connections
to many of Japan's major enterprises.
そうだ　日本の名だたる企業が
我々と裏で契約してる
A certain pharmaceutical company conducted
clinical tests on Ajins...
某製薬会社は
亜人で臨床実験を繰り返し―
until they developed a new drug
that vastly increased their profits.
開発した新薬で
ばく大な利益を上げた
There are also makers of body armor,
medical devices, ammunition...
他にも 保護具メーカー
医療器具メーカー　軍需産業
There are countless ways to use Ajins.
亜人の使い道は いくらでもある
So, Ajins can fuel the economy...
（戸崎）
経済動物か…
（木戸）
ああ　お前さんも
うまく立ち回れば―
Yeah, and if you play your cards right,
you can make big money, too.
でかい金がつかめる
（戸崎）
でかい金か… フッ
Big money, huh?
くっ…
くそ！
Damn it!
What can I do...?
At this rate... I might be disposed of...
どうする？　このままでは
最悪 始末される
Should I run?
逃げるか？
No, wait...
I should still have a chance...
いや 待て
まだ チャンスはあるはずだ
There's always a chance...
どんな時でもチャンスは…
くそ！
Damn it!
あっ…
Why do you want me to wear this, Mr. Sato?
（田中）
こんなの着せて どうすんすか？
佐藤さん
（佐藤）
君は寝たふりしてるだけでいいよ
All you have to do is pretend
to be sleeping.
（田中）
はあ…
Sure...
Are you listening, Tanaka?
（佐藤）
いいかい 田中君
You have to choose the best tactics
for any given situation...
戦略というのはだな
状況に合わせ 最も適した…
うん？
Is there a problem?
（田中）
何か問題でも？
I'm starting to feel like Hannibal.
（佐藤）
なんか ハンニバルみたく
なってきたなぁ
（田中）
はあ？
If I'm Hannibal, then you're...
（佐藤）
私がハンニバルだとすると 君は…
Clarice?
（田中）
クラリスっすか？
No, you're Murdoch.
（佐藤）
いや マードックだな　顔的に…
You've got the face for it.
（田中）
はあ？
Well, then let's get started.
（佐藤）
それじゃあ ひとつ 始めますかな
“作戦は 奇をもって
よしとすべし”だ
"I love it when a plan comes together!"
（ＳＰ）
オグラ博士
車に戻るのは まだ危険だ
Dr. Ogura, it's still too dangerous
to return to the car.
The rest of my cigarettes are in the car.
（オグラ）
予備のたばこが車なんだよ
（ＳＰ）
たばこなら 中で買えるだろ？
You can buy cigarettes in here, can't you?
This brand isn't made anymore.
So, the ones stocked up in the car are
（オグラ）
これは廃番の銘柄なの
だからもう
車にストックしてあるのしか…
-the only--
-Don't move.
動くな
（ＳＰ）
うっ！
Down on your knees.
Both hands behind your head.
ひざまずけ　両手は頭の後ろだ
Do you fully understand
what you're messing with?
力関係を分かってるのか？
If you make an enemy of us,
我々を敵に回せば お前も
お前の上司も ただでは済まんぞ
it won't end well for you
or your supervisors.
んっ…
（銃声）
（ＳＰ）おっ…
I told you not to move.
（戸崎）
動くなと言ったはずだ
（笑い声）
まさか
情報を出し惜しみしたことを―
You're not mad just because I wouldn't
share a little information, are you?
怒ってるのか？
Go ahead.
構わんよ
この世に未練はない
I've got nothing left to live for.
As long as I can have one last cigarette.
最後に１本吸えればな
（戸崎）はぁっ… はぁっ…
It's gotten awfully quiet...
（報道陣）
えらく静かになったな…
Security! What's going on in there?!
（キャスター）
警備の人！　何があったの？
-We can't contact anyone inside.
-What do we do?
（警備員）
中と連絡がつかんな
どうする？
All we can do is wait for word...
とにかく
指示があるまで待つしか…
あっ…
Who's that?
誰だ？
It appears that a man pushing a wheelchair
has come out of the laboratory!
（モニター音声：キャスター）
何でしょうか？
研究所から
車椅子を押す男が出てきました！
Is he a staff member?!
関係者でしょうか！？
（コウマ）
まずいな…
マスコミの連中 危ないぞ
This is bad... The press is in danger.
（報道陣）
おい　車椅子の 田中じゃないか？
Hey, isn't that Tanaka in the wheelchair?!
Tanaka?! The second Ajin in the country?!
（報道陣）
田中！？　国内２例目の？
間違いない！
ちょっといいですか？
There's no mistake! Do you have a moment?!
-Please, answer some questions!
-Get back!
（警備員）おい 入るな！
（報道陣）お話聞かせてください！
（警備員）下がって！
（警備員）下がれ！
Stop! Don't push!
（警備員）うあっ…
（警備員）ちょ ちょっと困るって
（報道陣）
田中さん！　すみません
（ざわめき）
The most important thing was timing.
（佐藤）
重要だったのはタイミング
Kei Nagai's capture and Ikuya Ogura's
return to Japan...
永井圭捕獲と
オグラ･イクヤ来日
and the press gathered in one place.
多くのマスコミが
１カ所に集まる―
All of it coming together today.
今日というタイミング
Today...
今日は…
I've come here today because there's
something I want the public to know.
今日は一般の方々に
知ってほしいことがあって―
ここへ来ました
Let me start by saying two things.
２つだけ 話を聞いてください
（田中）
何をする気だ？　佐藤さん
What is Mr. Sato planning?
My name is Sato.
私の名前は佐藤
I'm an Ajin.
亜人です
What? Did he say Ajin?
（報道陣）ええっ！？
（報道陣）亜人？
Is what you're saying true?
（報道陣）
それは本当ですか？
政府に拘束されることに
恐れはないんですか？
Aren't you afraid of being captured
by the government?!
（キャスター）
ふた… ２つの話というのは
何ですか？
What are the two things you want to say?!
The first is, there is a lot
of false information out there...
１つ目は―
いいかげんな情報に
流されないでほしいということです
Don't let it fool you.
In the early 2000s, there was a big story
that caused quite a commotion.
2000年代前半
あるニュースが世間を騒がせた
As you all know...
皆さんもご存じのとおり―
it was the news of Koji Tanaka here...
ここにいる田中功次氏に関する
ニュースです
（田中の父）
功次… おい 功次
Koji...
Hey, Koji--
What is it? Why so pale?
どした？　青い顔して
Dad... I... I'm an Ajin...
（田中）
おやじ… 俺… 亜人だった
Really? Are you sure it's not a mistake?
（田中の母）
何かの間違いじゃないのかい？
Then that's amazing!
（父）
なんだよ　すげぇじゃねぇか
What do you do if you find out
you're an Ajin?
亜人だったら… どうすんだ？
（ノック）
（報道陣）
すみませーん
Excuse me!
（田中）
あっ！
（報道陣）
いますよね？ お願いします
We know you're home.
田中さん！
お話聞かせてください
Mr. Tanaka, please, answer some questions!
田中さーん！
It has been three days since
the disappearance
（ラジオ音声:アナウンサー）
国内２例目の亜人
田中功次氏が行方をくらませてから
既に３日…
of Japan's second Ajin, Koji Tanaka.
Our program has decided to offer a reward
for Koji Tanaka!
（司会者）
当番組は田中功次に
賞金を出すことにしました！
（歓声）
The media got carried away,
and a TV show even offered a reward.
（佐藤）
報道は過熱し ついには
賞金を出す番組まで出ました
This time,
the same thing happened with Kei Nagai.
そして
今回の永井圭の事件も同様です
It's been treated like a public event,
まるで
イベント事のように扱われ―
and the media is feeding the frenzy
all over again.
また それをあおるような報道が
多く見られました
But they have no idea
what was waiting for him.
その先に
何が待っているのかも知らずに
Yes, we do!
（報道陣）
もちろん知ってますよ！
Is there a problem we should know about?!
（報道陣）
それの 何が問題なのですか？
It's true,
some people feel a little sorry for them.
確かに 少し可哀想という
意見はありますよね
After all, people discovered as Ajins have
to be taken into government custody...
亜人だと発覚した人は
その先 政府が保護し―
その管理下で生活しなければ
ならないわけですから
and live under their care.
政府が そう正式発表している
ことは知っています
I know that that's what the government has
officially announced. But I tell you...
が それは… うそです
it's a lie.
The government conducts
inhumane experiments on Ajins.
政府は亜人で
非人道的な人体実験を行っている
That's the second thing I have to say.
それが２つ目の話です
-What are you saying?!
-That's an urban legend!
（報道陣）何言ってんだ！
（報道陣）それこそ都市伝説でしょ
In 2005, a video was leaked
2005年に米軍が亜人を
人体実験する映像が流出し―
of the American government doing
experiments on Ajins.
問題になりました
Many people say that similar things
are happening here, too. But...
国内でも そういうことが
あるのではと言う人は多くいます
（キャスター）しかし…
（報道陣）しかしですね 佐藤さん
But Mr. Sato! Did you fall for that hoax
（報道陣）
あなたはそんなデマを信じて
不法侵入を犯し―
and illegally enter the lab
to break Tanaka out?!
田中氏を連れ出したんですか？
That's obviously a crime!!
（報道陣）
明らかな犯罪行為ですよ！
-I have proof.
-Where is it?
証拠はあります
（報道陣）
どこにあるんですか？
Well, I've already... uploaded it online.
既にウェブ上に
アップロードしました
（どよめき）
-Confirm this immediately!
-Do you have a connection?
（報道陣）すぐに確認しろ！
（報道陣）ネット 見れるか？
（研究員）
あ… アップされてます
-Ah, it's uploaded!
-Damn it.
（若井(わかい)）
ちっ…
その動画は―
Those top-secret videos were taken from
the home computer of an Ajin researcher!
ある亜人研究員の自宅ＰＣから
入手した極秘データです！
（報道陣）うわっ
（報道陣）これ 出来すぎてるだろ
Is this video even real?
（報道陣）
ＣＧだろ
前にも似たようなやつあったぞ
I've seen videos like this before.
（報道陣）
この記録情報 裏取れ
（佐藤）
こんなことが許されるはずがない！
This cannot be forgiven!
そうでしょう？　皆さん！
Don't you see that?!
I'm asking all of you here to please,
protest with me!
共に声を上げてください！
In two days... I will start a protest
in front of the Ministry.
２日後 私は抗議活動を行います！
場所は厚生労働省前！
一緒に戦ってください！
Please, come fight with me!
After all there is that chance...
自分自身が亜人だった時のために…
that one of you could turn out
to be a Ajin, too.
Do it...
（佐藤）
そして…
You must do it
for the happiness of us all.
一人ひとりの幸せのために
（爆発音）
（悲鳴）
（報道陣）うおっ…
Shit, get back!
（報道陣）
やばい！ 下がれ！
（ざわめき）
There has been an explosion!
What was that, Mr. Sato?!
Was that your...?
今のは何です？
佐藤さん　あれもあなたの…
あ… あっ
As for the incident at the laboratory
two days ago...
（役員）
一昨日に
研究所で起こった事件ですが―
佐藤と名乗った男の発言は
全くの事実無根であります
the words of the man calling himself Sato
were completely untrue
and without foundation.
We have also confirmed the deaths
of many guards, researchers...
また 多くの警備員 研究員
そして―
and Dr. Ikuya Ogura,
who was visiting Japan--
来日したオグラ･イクヤ氏の
死亡も確認されており…
It's today, isn't it?
今日… ですね
What are you going to do, Mr. Tosaki?
どうするつもりですか？　戸崎さん
省前は大変なことになります
There will be a huge scene
in front of the Ministry...
私は… どうなるんでしょうか？
So, then... what will happen to me?
What do you mean?
Nothing's going to change.
どうって… 何も変わらんよ
（男性）
あ？ 何もねぇよ
There's nothing here. Hey, am I on TV?
俺 テレビ映ってねぇ？
They said there'd be a protest
or something...
（女性）
なんか デモするって言ってたのに
What should we do?
（カメラマン）
どうします？
Let's at least record
some background shots.
（ディレクター）
一応 インサート撮っとくか
That wasn't enough to get people moving.
（戸崎）
あんなことで人間は動かない
それは多くの歴史が証明している
History has proven that repeatedly.
I DON'T WANNA DIE.
自分の身に火の粉が
かからない限り―
As long as it doesn't directly affect them
people can be completely disinterested.
どこまでも
無関心でいられる
NO WAY I'M GOING
それが我々の本質だ
That's our nature.
REAL? FAKE? AJIN EXPERIMENTS!
There are already countless
fake experimentation videos on the web.
そもそもウェブ上には―
実験動画のフェイクなど
山ほどある
No one can tell the difference
between the fakes and the real thing.
本物とフェイクを
見分けられる者などいない
-Speaking of that, did you see the video?
-Which one? The one where he was crushed?
（女性）
そういえば見た？ 動画
ああ 潰れるやつ？
Tonight, there will be a dramatic change
in the Japanese Ajin situation.
今夜
日本の亜人事情は大きく覆る
"Change dramatically"? Oh, please.
何が“大きく覆る”だ
I'll find all of the ones that escaped.
逃げたやつら
全員 見つけ出してやる
And then I swear
I'll cover the whole thing up.
そして必ず隠蔽(いんぺい)する
Let's go.
（戸崎）行くぞ
（泉）あ…
Where are we going?
（泉）
どこへ行くんです？
（田中）
フッフッ…
This plan wasn't aimed to gather humans.
（佐藤）
この作戦は
人間を集めるためのものじゃない
It's to gather Ajins.
亜人を集めるためのものだ
（田中）
はあ
Ajins will be able
to tell that those videos are real.
（佐藤）
亜人であれば
あの動画が本物だと見抜くだろう
The point in question is
the way you regenerate.
ポイントは“再生の仕方”
偽物とは出来が違う
It looks different from the fakes.
Also...
そして―
The part that really helps is
the broadcast
駄目押しが 永井君と我々が
逃げる様子を放送させたこと
of you and Kei Nagai escaping.
"Even if we're caught, we can escape."
捕まっても逃げられた
When the Ajins see that example,
この実例は亜人に安心感を与え
名乗り出やすくする
they'll feel safer
and more likely to come forward.
そして私は信頼される
And they'll trust me.
うーん… ふぅ
This is our starting point.
ようやくスタートポイントだ
国を変えるぞ　田中くん
We're going to change the country, Tanaka.
（田中）
フッフッ…
あんたの作戦どおりだぜ
佐藤さん
It's exactly as you planned, Mr. Sato...
Thanks for coming.
（田中ＩＢＭ）
よく来てくれた
これから本当の集合場所を伝える
Now I'll tell you
the real gathering place.
Tomorrow at two p.m.
明日の午後２時…
そこに来てほしい
We want you to meet there.
あ… 死んだ
Oh, I died.
（泉）
あ… ああっ…
This is...
ここは…
あの 私…
I...
その… 戸崎さん？
Mr. Tosaki?
えっ？
こ… これは？
What is this?
You brought the FK, right?
ＦＫは持ってきたんだろうな？
戸崎さん
これは さすがに まずいのでは？
Mr. Tosaki...
You know this can't be good...
（戸崎）
問題ない　ボディーガードを
撃ったのは帽子の銃だ
It's not a problem.
The bodyguard was shot by Hat's gun.
No one will suspect me.
私が怪しまれることはない
この男は 原形が分からないほど
八つ裂きにされた研究員の―
I switched this man with a researcher
who'd been mauled beyond recognition.
死体と入れ替わってもらった
And faked his dental records.
歯の治療痕のカルテを改ざんしてな
し… しかし
-But--
-That day...
あの日 私は再確認したんだ
I swore to myself
that I will reach my goal,
“どれだけ他人を不幸にしようと
目的を達成する”と
no matter the cost to others.
全て出してもらうぞ
あんたが握っているもの 全て
I'll take everything.
Whatever you've got, I want it.
If you bring me my FKs.
（オグラ）
ＦＫを持ってきたらな
（戸崎）
論文同様 ふざけた男だ
As you can see, he's a joke of a man.
日本の研究員が
ああ言うのも分かる
I can see why the Japanese researchers
treat him like they do.
I can't understand why
the U.S. accepted him.
あっちの国で受け入れられたのが
不思議でならない
天才なんだよ
Because I'm a genius.
UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
（少年）
ひゅー おっと…
うん？
（戸崎）
ん？　迷子か？
Are you lost?
That lady... what's wrong with her?
（少年）
あの人 どうしたの？
She hasn't woken up since her accident.
事故で目が覚めないんだ
Oh... poor lady.
（少年）
へえ 可哀想
That's right. She is a poor lady.
そうだ　可哀想な人だった
"No matter what,
there's always a chance to start over."
“どんな時でも
やり直すチャンスはあるはず”
それが あの人の口癖だった
That was what she always said.
But then this happened.
でも こうなってしまった
She was living with the debts
her parents left her...
親の残した借金を
背負って生きて―
Because of that, she couldn't afford
to pay for health insurance.
そのせいで 健康保険に
入る余裕すらなかったんだ
（少年）
うーん…
Unfortunately that means it will cost
a lot of money to save her.
彼女を治すには
お金が たくさん必要ってことだよ
And who are you?
Are you a friend of the lady?
お兄さん あの人の友達？
I'm her fiancé.
（戸崎）
婚約者だ
I hope she gets better.
（少年）
治るといいね
（戸崎）
ああ…
Yeah...
I'll do whatever it takes
to make her happy.
彼女だけは幸せにしてみせる
No matter who I have to send to hell
to do so.
世界中の誰を地獄に落としても
（圭）
はぁっ…
（せきこみ）
はぁっ… ああ…
I've gotten used to pain...
痛いのは慣れてきたけど―
But drowning...
溺れるのは… はぁっ…
苦しいなぁ
freaking sucks.
うっ… うっ… はぁっ…
ううっ… やっぱ 人助けなんて…
Rescuing people...
ああ… はぁ…
really isn't worth the effort at all.
するもんじゃないなぁ
ああ… はぁ…
（手をたたく音）
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
これで全員かな？
Is this everyone?
上がってきてくれ
Come on in.
TO BE CONTINUED
If my wish would come true
願い叶(かな)うなら
もう一度
Once again
I wanna touch your heart
君の心に
触れていたい
どんな闇でも
探してるんだ
No matter how dark it gets
I'll be searching
For my one
たったひとつの
光を
And only light
As I look up to the stars
Even though you are far
遠いけど
You're looking up at the same starry sky
同じ星空　見上げてる
In the sky of my heart
心の空には
雫(こぼ)れ落ちそうな
It's about to spill over
Your smile and
君の笑顔と
ぬくもり
Your warmth
Hear me
Until I went away and
Faced the lonely days
I thought I could understand
愛することの意味なんて
What it means to love
分かってたつもりだった
Feeling everything that
Was right in front of me
大切なもの失って
Losing something precious
Realizing real love
本当の愛に気付いて
I'll tell you now
I'll tell you now,
Just how close you are